# Cameron Wright

Berkeley, California, United States



cam.mac.wright@gmail.com



(805)748-4937



linkedin.com/in/cameron--wright

## Summary

First and foremost, I love writing code. Ever since writing my first program in Visual Basic and manipulating it to solve a desired problem, I have cultivated a keen interest in the idea of solving real-world problems with software applications. Today, I employ my knowledge of Javascript to solve the never-ending puzzle of how to create a program that does exactly what I want it to do. I strongly believe in the power of programming to transform and improve the lives of people around the world--particularly when it comes to accessibility. When I design software I am mindful that it is not right to exclude anyone from accessing a website.

Currently--I work in teams to develop various web apps while navigating version control and sequential processing.

Even on my own time, I tend to continue writing code. Most recently I have worked on a website for my pickle-ball group's tournament play. I love staying engaged and competitive in a variety of activities--whether it's Scrabble in local tournaments or competing on the national stage in sailing competitions. I find a beautiful crossover in the pursuits that allow me to utilize my skills in software development while pursuing my interests in the things that I love: creativity, organization, problem solving, competitive-spirit, and an enjoyment for the natural world. This is what drives my passion--a never ending thirst to create beautiful, powerful things and share them with the world.

# **Experience**



#### Lead Bartender

StrEat Brew

Aug 2018 - Present (2 years 6 months +)

# Software Quality Assurance Tester

**VGM** 

Apr 2019 - Sep 2019 (6 months)

Recruited to evaluate mission-critical information for confidential multi-million dollar projects at industry dominant research company (subject to a non-disclosure agreement; no further details available).



#### **QA** Tester

**Epic Games** 

Dec 2014 - Jan 2017 (2 years 2 months)

First phase alpha-testing and box-testing for Epic Games' title called Fortnite.

Handled sensitive information--agreed to NDA--can't go until full detail.

Bug Reporting | Balance Testing | QA Missing Features | Content Feedback

# Data Analyst

MindBlown LLC

Feb 2016 - Jun 2016 (5 months) Bound to NDA.

Aggregated mission-critical and sensitive data and implemented research-based analysis of data. Developed a strategy for data optimization. Defined parameters to flag information of interest.

Helped monetize a new app called Thrive N' Shine (Financial Planning Tool/App for Youth) in a 9person team. Native app available on both iOS and Android.

#### Education



### **UC Berkeley Extension**

Certificate in Full Stack Software Development, Computer Software Engineering 2020 - 2021

Learning the tools of full-stack web development:

Javascript | CSS | HTML | CSS Frameworks | React | Node.js | Git Bash Powershell & Command Line Interface

#### Willamette University

2014 - 2015

Voted Freshman Class President

Worked in teams to develop better student-success sustainability measures.



#### 🤊 San Luis Obispo High School

2010 - 2014

#### Skills

Time Management • CSS • JavaScript • Software Development • Microsoft Office • PowerPoint

#### **Honors & Awards**



Eagle Scout Award - Boy Scouts of America

Apr 2014



#### LaunchPad Award/Scholarship - UC Berkeley

Awarded by a panel of judges to a promising student in tech who exemplifies a commitment to excellence.



#### **Leadership Award/Scholarship** - Willamette University

Sep 2014